{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The small child does whatever his father was done.", "opta": "has done", "optb": "did", "optc": "does", "optd": "had done", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "You need not come unless you want to.", "opta": "You don't need to come unless you want to", "optb": "You come only when you want to", "optc": "You come unless you don't want to", "optd": "You needn't come until you don't want to", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "There are not many men who are so famous that they are frequently referred to by their short names only", "opta": "initials", "optb": "signatures", "optc": "pictures", "optd": "middle names", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The man to who I sold my house was a cheat.", "opta": "to whom I sell", "optb": "to who I sell", "optc": "who was sold to", "optd": "to whom I sold", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "They were all shocked at his failure in the competition.", "opta": "were shocked at all", "optb": "had all shocked at", "optc": "had all shocked by", "optd": "had been all shocked on", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I need not offer any explanation regarding this incident - my behaviour is speaking itself.", "opta": "will speak to itself", "optb": "speaks for itself", "optc": "has been speaking", "optd": "speaks about itself", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He is too important for tolerating any delay.", "opta": "to tolerate", "optb": "to tolerating", "optc": "at tolerating", "optd": "with tolerating", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The population of Tokyo is greater than that of any other town in the world.", "opta": "greatest among any other", "optb": "greater than all other", "optc": "greater than those of any other", "optd": "greater than any other", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The performance of our players was rather worst than I had expected.", "opta": "bad as I had expected", "optb": "worse than I had expected", "optc": "worse than expectation", "optd": "worst than was expected", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why did you not threw the bag away?", "opta": "did you not throw", "optb": "had you not threw", "optc": "did you not thrown", "optd": "you did not thrown", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Shapes of gods and goddess are worshipped by people.", "opta": "Images", "optb": "Reflections", "optc": "Clay shapes", "optd": "Clay toys", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In addition to enhanced their reputations through strategic use of philanthropy, companies are sponsoring  social initiatives to open new markets.", "opta": "of enhancing their reputation", "optb": "to having enhance their reputation", "optc": "to enhancing their reputation", "optd": "to have their reputation enhancing", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The intruder stood quietly for few moments", "opta": "for few time", "optb": "for the few moments", "optc": "for moments", "optd": "for a few moments", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The police has so far succeeded in recovering only a part of the stolen property.", "opta": "thus far succeeded for recovery", "optb": "so far succeeded in recovery of", "optc": "as for as succeeded in recovery of", "optd": "so far succeeded to recover", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He confidentially asked the crowd if they thought he was right and the crowd shouted that they did.", "opta": "that he did", "optb": "that they had", "optc": "that he is", "optd": "that he didn't", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why should the candidates be afraid of English Language is not clear.", "opta": "the candidates should be", "optb": "do the candidates be", "optc": "should be the candidates", "optd": "are the candidates", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He found the gold coin as he cleans the floor.", "opta": "as he had cleaned", "optb": "while he cleans", "optc": "which he is cleaning", "optd": "while cleaning", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He admired the speed with which he completed the work and appreciating the method adopted by him", "opta": "appreciate the method being adopted", "optb": "appreciated the method adopted", "optc": "appreciate the method of adoption", "optd": "appreciated the method adopting method", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Maria unnecessarily picked up a quarrel with Rani and left the party hurried.", "opta": "has picked up", "optb": "picked on", "optc": "picked", "optd": "picking up", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "She cooks, washes dishes, does her homework and then relaxing.", "opta": "relaxing then", "optb": "then is relaxing", "optc": "relaxing is then", "optd": "then relaxes", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Acquisition of certain specific skills can be facilitated from general awareness, education to novel situations", "opta": "can be facilitated by", "optb": "may facilitate through", "optc": "can be felicitated with", "optd": "may be felicitated with", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He never has and ever will take such strong measures.", "opta": "had taken nor will ever take", "optb": "had taken and will ever take", "optc": "has and never will take", "optd": "had and ever will take", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Technology must use to feed the forces of change.", "opta": "must be used to feed", "optb": "must have been using to feed", "optc": "must use having fed", "optd": "must be using to feed", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Anyone interested in the use of computers can learn much if you have access to a personal computer.", "opta": "they have access", "optb": "access can be available", "optc": "he or she has access", "optd": "one of them have access", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "They are not beware of all the facts", "opta": "are not aware for", "optb": "are not aware of", "optc": "are not to be aware", "optd": "must not to be aware for", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We can not always convey ourselves in simple sentences.", "opta": "cannot always convey", "optb": "can not always express", "optc": "cannot always express", "optd": "can not always communicate", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does agonise me most is not this criticism, but the trivial reason behind it.", "opta": "most agonising me", "optb": "agonises me most", "optc": "agonising me most", "optd": "I most agonised", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As there was no time, the remaining items were deferred into the next meeting.", "opta": "are deferred till", "optb": "were deferred till", "optc": "were deferred to", "optd": "had deferred with", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Despite of their differences on matters of principles, they all agree on the demand of hike is salary?", "opta": "Despite their", "optb": "Despite of the", "optc": "Despite for their", "optd": "Despite off their", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The man who has committed such a serious crime must get the mostly severe punishment.", "opta": "be getting the mostly severely", "optb": "get the most severe", "optc": "have got the most severely", "optd": "have been getting the severe most", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For many centuries in Indian History there was no city so famous like the city of Ujjain.", "opta": "as", "optb": "such as", "optc": "likewise", "optd": "so like", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We don't know how did the thief made an escape.", "opta": "how the thief did make", "optb": "how the thief does make", "optc": "how the thief made", "optd": "how was the thief made", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He is a singer of repute, but his yesterday's performance was quite disappointing.", "opta": "performances of yesterday were", "optb": "yesterday performance was", "optc": "yesterday performance were", "optd": "performances about yesterday were", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Their earnings are such that they find it difficult to make both ends to meet.", "opta": "to makings both ends meet", "optb": "to make both ends for meeting", "optc": "to make both ends meet", "optd": "for making both ends to meet", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He has received no other message than an urgent telegram asking him to rush his village immediately.", "opta": "asked him to rush his village", "optb": "asking him to have rush his village", "optc": "asking him to rush to his village", "optd": "asking him rushing at his village", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One of the most significant phenomenons of our time has been the development of cinema.", "opta": "phenomenon", "optb": "phenomena", "optc": "phenomenonna", "optd": "phenomenonns", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Had you been told me about your problem, I would have helped you.", "opta": "If you would have told", "optb": "Had you have told", "optc": "had you told", "optd": "If you have told", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It was until many years later that Gandhi became a rebel against authority.", "opta": "It was not until many years", "optb": "It was till many years", "optc": "It was not many years", "optd": "Until It was many years", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Anand has the guts to rise from the occasion and come out successfully.", "opta": "in rising from", "optb": "to raise with", "optc": "to rise to", "optd": "to rise against", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If you are thinking about investigation overseas, isn't it makes sense to find an experience guide?", "opta": "it is not making", "optb": "doesn't it make", "optc": "does it make", "optd": "is it making", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This is one of the most important inventions of this century.", "opta": "invention of this century", "optb": "invention of these century", "optc": "invention of centuries", "optd": "invention of the centuries", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The orator had been left the auditorium before the audience stood up.", "opta": "had been leaving", "optb": "was left", "optc": "had left", "optd": "would leave", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He dislikes the word dislike, isn't he", "opta": "didn't he", "optb": "doesn't he", "optc": "hasn't he", "optd": "does he", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We must take it granted that Madhu will not come for today's function.", "opta": "take it for granted", "optb": "taking it granted", "optc": "took it as granted", "optd": "have it granted", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The research study is an eye-opener and attempts to acquaint us with the problems of poor nations.", "opta": "attempted to acquaint", "optb": "attempts at acquainting", "optc": "attempt to acquaint", "optd": "attempting to acquaint", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It was unanimously resolved that the parties should unitedly undertook launching of popular programmes.", "opta": "should be united undertook", "optb": "should be unitedly undertaken", "optc": "should be unitedly undertake", "optd": "should unitedly undertake", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "They continued to work in the field despite of the heavy rains.", "opta": "even though there is heavy rain", "optb": "although heavily rains", "optc": "in spite the heavy rains", "optd": "even though it rained heavily", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is always better to make people realise the importance of discipline than to impose them on it.", "opta": "impose it with them", "optb": "impose them with it", "optc": "imposing them on it", "optd": "impose it on them", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "My doctor knew that I would eventually recover and do kind of work I would be doing before", "opta": "would have been doing", "optb": "would have done", "optc": "had been done", "optd": "had been doing", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Later he became unpopular because he tried to lord it on his followers.", "opta": "to lord it for", "optb": "to lord over", "optc": "to lord it over", "optd": "to lord it over on", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The crops are dying; it must not had rained.", "opta": "must had not", "optb": "must not be", "optc": "must not have", "optd": "must not have been", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The courts are actively to safeguard the interests and the rights of the poor.", "opta": "are actively to safeguarding", "optb": "have been actively safeguarding", "optc": "have to active in safeguarding", "optd": "are actively in safeguarding", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The drama had many scenes which were so humorous that it was hardly possible to keep a straight face.", "opta": "hardly possible for keeping", "optb": "hardly impossible for keeping", "optc": "hardly impossible for keep", "optd": "hardly possible keeping", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hardly does the sun rise when the stars disappeared.", "opta": "have the sun rose", "optb": "had the sun risen", "optc": "did the sun rose", "optd": "the sun rose", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "You will be late if you do not leave now", "opta": "did not leave", "optb": "left", "optc": "will not leave", "optd": "do not happen to leave", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The train will leave at 8.30 pm, we have been ready by 7.30pm so that, we can reach the station in time.", "opta": "were", "optb": "must be", "optc": "are", "optd": "should have", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All the allegations levelled against him were found to be baseless.", "opta": "level against", "optb": "level with", "optc": "levelling with", "optd": "levelled for", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ramesh is as tall if not,  taller than Mahesh.", "opta": "not as tall but", "optb": "not so tall but as", "optc": "as tall as, if not", "optd": "as if not", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He hesitated to listen to what his brother was saying.", "opta": "listened to hesitate", "optb": "hesitated listen to", "optc": "hesitates to listening", "optd": "is hesitated to listen to", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The prosecution failed in establish in every case today.", "opta": "to", "optb": "on", "optc": "as", "optd": "upon", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One of my drawbacks is that I do not have to tolerance of ambiguity.", "opta": "do not have", "optb": "cannot have", "optc": "am not", "optd": "did not have to", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "They should have calmly thought of the advantages that would accrue to them.", "opta": "should have been calm in thinking about", "optb": "should be calmly thought of", "optc": "shall have to calmly thought of", "optd": "should have calmly think of", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The easiest of the thing to do is to ask the address to the postman.", "opta": "of the things to do", "optb": "among the things did", "optc": "of the thing to be done", "optd": "of all the things done", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We demonstrated to them how we were prepared the artistic patterns.", "opta": "are prepared", "optb": "have prepared", "optc": "are preparing", "optd": "had prepared", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Because of his mastery in this field, his suggestions are wide accepted.", "opta": "are widely accepted", "optb": "widely acceptance", "optc": "have widely accepted", "optd": "have been wide accepted", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "They felt humiliated because they realised that they had cheated.", "opta": "have been cheated", "optb": "had been cheated", "optc": "had been cheating", "optd": "were to be cheated", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Tax evaders should heavily punished as they do it intentionally.", "opta": "should be heavy fined", "optb": "should have heavily fined", "optc": "shall have heavy fine", "optd": "should be heavily fined", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We met him immediately after the session in which he had been given a nice speech.", "opta": "would be giving", "optb": "has been given", "optc": "will have given", "optd": "had given", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For some days the new professor lectured above the heads of his pupils.", "opta": "over the head of", "optb": "over the heads of", "optc": "on the heads of", "optd": "through the heds of", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The accused now flatly denies have admitted his guilt in his first statement.", "opta": "having admitted", "optb": "had admitted", "optc": "have been admitting", "optd": "has admitting", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We were still standing in the queue when the film was beginning.", "opta": "film began", "optb": "film had begun", "optc": "beginning of the film was over", "optd": "film begins", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If I would have realised the nature of job earlier, I would not have accepted it.", "opta": "If I have had", "optb": "In case I would have", "optc": "Had I been", "optd": "Had I", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The crime has growth rapidly in Russia since the disintegration of the communist system.", "opta": "rapid crime has grown", "optb": "crime has grown rapidly", "optc": "crimes grow rapidly", "optd": "crimes have been rapidly grown", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The crime has grown rapidly in Russia since the disintegration of the communist system."}, {"question": "They failed in their attempt to repair the demolished portion of that building.", "opta": "for their attempt to repair", "optb": "in their attempting to repair", "optc": "with their attempt to repair", "optd": "in their attempt for repairs", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I earnestly believe that you will visit our relatives during your forthcoming trip to Mumbai.", "opta": "had hardly believe that", "optb": "sincerely would believe", "optc": "certainly believing that", "optd": "could not believe", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "By such time you finish that chapter, I will write a letter.", "opta": "The time when", "optb": "By the time", "optc": "By that time", "optd": "The time", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Though we have kept in mind to try and maintain most facilities, we would like to request you to kindly bear with us any inconvenience that may be caused.", "opta": "must keep in mind to try and maintain", "optb": "have kept in mind trying and maintain", "optc": "would keep in mind to try and to maintain", "optd": "should have kept in mind to try and to maintain", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The tea-estate administration is in such mess there is no leader to set the things right.", "opta": "in such a mess here", "optb": "in a such mess that here", "optc": "in such a mess that there", "optd": "with such a mess that there", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "They examined both the samples very carefully but failed to detect any difference in them.", "opta": "some difference in", "optb": "some difference between", "optc": "any difference between", "optd": "any difference among", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\"Friends and comrades, the light has gone away from our lives and there is darkness everywhere\"", "opta": "off", "optb": "out of", "optc": "out from", "optd": "out off", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Because of his ill health, the doctor has advised him not to refrain from  smoking.", "opta": "to not refrain from", "optb": "to resort to", "optc": "to refrain from", "optd": "to be refrained from", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "They have a scheme of rewarding the best of the performers every year.", "opta": "a best performer", "optb": "the best among the performer", "optc": "a best among performer", "optd": "the best of the performer", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What happens to all those travellers on the ship was not known?", "opta": "What happened of", "optb": "What happened in", "optc": "What is that happens to", "optd": "What happened to", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Making friends is more rewarding than to make enemies.", "opta": "to be unsociable", "optb": "to be sociable", "optc": "being unsociable", "optd": "making enemies", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The moment they saw me, they were delight", "opta": "had delighted", "optb": "were delighted", "optc": "are delighted", "optd": "have been delighted", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He should not had done it.", "opta": "had not", "optb": "should had not", "optc": "should not have", "optd": "should have", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "No sooner do the bells ring than the curtain rose.", "opta": "did the bell ring", "optb": "did the bells ring", "optc": "had the bell rang", "optd": "had the bell rung", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The moment the manager came to know fraudulent action of his assistant, he order immediately dismissed him.", "opta": "immediately ordered his dismissed", "optb": "ordered his immediate dismissal", "optc": "immediately order dismissal of his", "optd": "ordered for immediately dismissal of him", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The meeting was attended to by all invitees.", "opta": "all attended to by", "optb": "attended by all", "optc": "fully attended to by", "optd": "like attending to all", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If he has to spend five hours in the queue, it was really a wastage.", "opta": "is a really wastage", "optb": "is real a wastage", "optc": "has really a wastage", "optd": "is really a wastage", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The world has seen small real attempt at population and resource planning.", "opta": "few", "optb": "little", "optc": "less", "optd": "a few", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "My hair stood off ends when I saw the horrible sight.", "opta": "stood at ends", "optb": "stood on ends", "optc": "stood to ends", "optd": "stands on ends", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The long or short of it is that I do not want to deal with that new firm.", "opta": "The long and short of it", "optb": "The long and short for it", "optc": "The long or short for it", "optd": "The shot and long for it", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Can you tell me why did you not speak the truth?", "opta": "why did not you speak", "optb": "that why did you not speak", "optc": "why you did not speak", "optd": "why did you not spoke", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The people generally try to curry favour with the corrupt but influential person.", "opta": "cook favour", "optb": "seek favour", "optc": "extract favour", "optd": "display favour", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I have got some tea, but I do not have a sugar.", "opta": "some", "optb": "got", "optc": "more", "optd": "any", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Had I realised how close I was to the edge of the valley, I would not have carried the bags there.", "opta": "Had I been realised", "optb": "If I would have realised", "optc": "When I realised", "optd": "Had I had realised", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most of the Indian workers are as healthy as, if not healthier than, British workers.", "opta": "as if healthy as not healthier", "optb": "healthier but not as healthy", "optc": "as healthy, if not healthier", "optd": "so healthy, if not healthier", "opte": "No correction required", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}